{"name": "D05 2021-4", "questions": [{"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "1. The 1st term in the geometric sequence below is -13. If it can be determined, what is the 6th term?-13, 26, -52, 104, -208, ...", "choices": {"A": "-416", "B": "-312", "C": "312", "D": "416", "E": "Cannot be determined from the given information"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "2.  In the standard (x, y) coordinate plane, point A has coordinates (-7, -5). Point A is translated 7 units to the left and 5 units down, and that image is labeled A'. What are the coordinates of A' ?", "choices": {"A": "(-14, -10)", "B": "(-12, -12)", "C": "(-7, -10)", "D": "(0, 0)", "E": "(14, 10)"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "3.  Olga worked on a project for  hours on each of 6 workdays. On the 7th day of working on the project, Olga worked  of the time she had worked each of the previous workdays to complete the project. How many hours did it take Olga to complete the project?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "30", "D": "33", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "4. Given that 5 pounds of coffee makes exactly 210 servings, how many pounds of coffee makes exactly 70 servings?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "2", "C": "", "D": "", "E": "15"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "5.  For shown below, point S is on RT, the length of RS is 10 cm, and the length of ST is 18 cm. What is the distance, in centimeters, between T and the midpoint of RS ?", "choices": {"A": "14", "B": "18", "C": "19", "D": "23", "E": "28"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "6. For all real values of p and r, which of the following expressions is equivalent to p(2-r) + 8(p-r)?", "choices": {"A": "6p - 9r", "B": "6p - 8r", "C": "6p - 8r - pr", "D": "10p - 2r", "E": "10p - 8r - pr"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "7.  Fifty shoppers at a pet store were asked if they owned at least 1 cat or at least 1 dog. Data from their answers were recorded below.How many of these shoppers said that they owned NEITHER a cat NOR a dog?", "choices": {"A": "0", "B": "6", "C": "7", "D": "13", "E": "43"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "8. Yvette has 6 pairs of leggings, 2 pairs of shoes, and 6 T-shirts, which all go together well. How many different groupings consisting of 1 of her 6 pairs of leggings, 1 of her 2 pairs of shoes, and 1 of her 6 T-shirts are available for Yvette to wear?", "choices": {"A": "8", "B": "12", "C": "14", "D": "24", "E": "72"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "9. According to the United States Department of Commerce, the approximate area of Rhode Island is 1.5 x 103 square miles and the approximate area of Alaska is 6.6 x 105 square miles. Using these measurements, which of the following is closest to the ratio of the area of Alaska to the area of Rhode Island?", "choices": {"A": "22:5", "B": "440:1", "C": "484:25", "D": "510:1", "E": "810:1"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "10. Rectangle A has a length of 64 inches and a width of 48 inches. Rectangle B has a length and a width that are both  times the length and the width of Rectangle A. Rectangle C has a length and a width that are both  times the length and the width of Rectangle B. What is the perimeter, in inches, of Rectangle C?", "choices": {"A": "63", "B": "84", "C": "126", "D": "168", "E": "224"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "11. The expression (x6)3 is equivalent to:", "choices": {"A": "x9", "B": "x18", "C": "x216", "D": "3x3", "E": "3x5"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "12. A king-sized inflatable rectangular bed when fully inflated will have inside dimensions, in inches, of 78 by 75 by 5. An air pump can pump air into the bed at a rate of 100 cubic inches per second. At that rate, which of the following is closest to the number of seconds it will take to fully inflate the bed?", "choices": {"A": "58", "B": "62", "C": "158", "D": "293", "E": "1,170"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "13. Jake wants to build a scale model of his house. The house is 48 feet long and 32 feet wide, and it is 30 feet tall at the highest point. Jake wants the model to be 8 inches long. How wide, in inches, should his mode be?", "choices": {"A": "5", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "12", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "14. You see a circle graph in a newspaper article about student employment, but no percentages are given for the sectors. You want to use the information contained in the graph in a report for your sociology class. You measure the central angle of the sector titled \"work during the week\" with your protractor, and it measures 144\u00b0. According to the circle graph and  your measurement, the \"work during the week\" sector is what percent, to the nearest percent, of the circle graph?", "choices": {"A": "40%", "B": "30%", "C": "25%", "D": "14%", "E": " Cannot be determined from the given information"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "15. Josiah stands on level ground 15 ft from the base of a cliff. The angle of elevation from where Josiah is standing to the top of the cliff is 50\u00b0, as shown below. Which of the following values is closest to the height, in feet, of the cliff?(Note: sin50\u00b0 \u2248 0.8; cos50\u00b0  \u2248 0.6; tan50\u00b0  \u2248 1.2)", "choices": {"A": "12", "B": "13", "C": "18", "D": "25", "E": "60"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "16. Consider the line 3x - 4y = 6 in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane. For the point on this line with x-coordinate equal to 3, what is the y-coordinate?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "17. What is the solution set to the equation x2 - x = 12 ?", "choices": {"A": "{-4, 3}", "B": "{-3, 4}", "C": "{-2, 6}", "D": "{12, 13}", "E": "{13}"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "18. The vertices of \u25b3PQR are given in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane below. What is the area, in square coordinate units, of \u25b3PQR ?", "choices": {"A": "6", "B": "8", "C": "12", "D": "24", "E": "28"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "19.  In the standard (x, y) coordinate plane, a line intersects the y-axis at (0, 2) and contains the point (8, 5). What is the slope of the line?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "20. One of the following values for a makes the expression undefined. Which one?", "choices": {"A": "-3", "B": "", "C": "-1", "D": "0", "E": "i"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "21. What is the least positive number that has a remainder of 3 when divided by 5 and a remainder of 7 when divided by 9?", "choices": {"A": "24", "B": "35", "C": "43", "D": "45", "E": "78"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "22. Two warning signs begin flashing at the same time. One sign flashes every 3 seconds, and the other sign flashes every 8 seconds. How many seconds elapse from the moment the 2 signs flash at the same time until they next flash at the same time?", "choices": {"A": "5", "B": "5.5", "C": "11", "D": "12", "E": "24"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "23. Sets A, B, and C are defined below.A = {1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6}B = {2, 4, 6}C = {1, 2}A number will be randomly selected from set A. What is the probability that the selected number will be an element of set B and an element of set C?", "choices": {"A": "0", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "24. What rational number is exactly halfway between  and  on the real number line?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "25. The circle that has a center of (-3, 4) and is tangent to the y-axis is graphed in the standard (x, y)coordinate plane below. What is the area, in square coordinate units, of this circle?", "choices": {"A": "6\u03c0", "B": "8\u03c0", "C": "9\u03c0", "D": "16\u03c0", "E": "18\u03c0"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "26. An 8-sided game piece with faces numbered from 1 to 8 is rolled twice. What is the probability that an 8 is rolled both times?(Note: Assume that each side has an equally likely chance of being rolled.)", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "27.  When (3x - 2)4 is expanded and the like terms are combined, what is the coefficient of the x4 term?", "choices": {"A": "9", "B": "12", "C": "16", "D": "48", "E": "81"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "28. Bo and Tia will balance perfectly on the seesaw shown below if w1 \u00d7 d1 = w2 \u00d7 d2, where w1, and d1, are the weight of Bo and his distance from the fulcrum, respectively, and w2 and d2 are similarly defined for Tia. Bo weighs 60 pounds and is sitting  feet from the fulcrum. Tia weighs  Bo's weight. What distance in feet, from the fulcrum must Tia sit in order for Bo and Tia to balance perfectly on the seesaw?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "29. Given that 3(x - 2) = 6x - 3, what is the value of 9x - 2 ?", "choices": {"A": "-29", "B": "-11", "C": "-5", "D": "1", "E": "7"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "30.  Ally is planting flowers around her square patio. The region she is planting is a 1-foot-wide strip that runs along 3 sides of her 5-foot-by-5-foot patio, as shown below. What is the area, in square feet, of the shaded region where Ally is planting flowers?", "choices": {"A": "5", "B": "11", "C": "15", "D": "17", "E": "19"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "31. Consider 3 circles: A, B, and C. The sum of the radii of Circle A and Circle B is 5 m. The sum of the radii of Circle A and Circle C is 8 m. The sum of the radii of Circle B and Circle C is 7 m. What is the length, in meters, of the radius of Circle C ?", "choices": {"A": "1", "B": "2", "C": "3", "D": "4", "E": "5"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "32. What is the complex conjugate of the number below?2 + 3i", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "-3i", "C": "3i", "D": "2-3i", "E": "2+3i"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "33. The function P(x) = x3 -10x2 + 9x - 90, where x is the number of items sold, models the profit P(x), in dollars, for Company A. The company breaks even when the profit is $0. How many items must Company A sell to break even?", "choices": {"A": "0", "B": "3", "C": "9", "D": "10", "E": "90"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "34. Which of the following statements shows that any subtraction can be written instead as an addition?", "choices": {"A": "a - b = |a| + |-b|", "B": "a - b = |-a| + |b|", "C": "a - b = a + |-b|", "D": "a - b = a + (-b)", "E": "a - b = (-a) + b"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "35.  What is the value of  ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "1", "E": "2"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "36. Given f(x) = -x - 4 and h(x) = 2x + 3, what is h(f(x))?", "choices": {"A": "-2x - 5", "B": "2x - 1", "C": "2x - 5", "D": "-2x2 - 11x - 12", "E": "2x2 + 11x - 12"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "37. Rectangle JKLM is shown below. The given side lengths are in feet. What is the cosine of \u2220KJL?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "38. The first 3 elements of a pattern are shown below. Each element is composed of small squares that are 18 inches wide and 18 inches long. Each element after the 1st element is a square that is 18 inches wider and 18 inches longer than the previous element. What is the area, in square feet, of the 4th element?", "choices": {"A": "6", "B": "9", "C": "16", "D": "24", "E": "36"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "39. The operation \u0398 is defined on the set of positive integers by the rule a \u0398 b = a + b2. What is the value of (4 \u0398 3) \u0398 5?", "choices": {"A": "34", "B": "38", "C": "44", "D": "50", "E": "74"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "40. The number a is a positive integer greater than 1. The number b is a negative integer. The number ab is:", "choices": {"A": "zero.", "B": "positive.", "C": "negative.", "D": "irrational.", "E": "an integer."}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "41. Use the following information to answer questions 41-43.The table below is part of a delivery truck log used in Aaron's trucking business. \"Mileage out\" and \"Mileage in\" represent the truck's mileage readings when it leaves the office and when it returns to the office, respectively, giving only the last 3 digits of the cumulative mileage reading. The \"Hours away\" column gives the amount of time from when the truck leaves the office until it returns to the office. When moving, the truck travels at an average speed of 50 miles per hour and does not travel more than 1,000 miles in any given day. Driver Ben forgot to complete the log for June 18.41. According to the mileage reading, what distance, in miles, did the truck travel on June 20?", "choices": {"A": "234", "B": "241", "C": "250", "D": "253", "E": "256"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "42. Use the following information to answer questions 41-43.The table below is part of a delivery truck log used in Aaron's trucking business. \"Mileage out\" and \"Mileage in\" represent the truck's mileage readings when it leaves the office and when it returns to the office, respectively, giving only the last 3 digits of the cumulative mileage reading. The \"Hours away\" column gives the amount of time from when the truck leaves the office until it returns to the office. When moving, the truck travels at an average speed of 50 miles per hour and does not travel more than 1,000 miles in any given day. Driver Ben forgot to complete the log for June 18.42. The figure shown below represents the route traveled on July 16. Aaron started at the office, drove 75 miles due north to the 1st stop, then 40 miles due east to the 2nd stop, and then 105 miles due south to the last stop. On his return trip, Aaron drove a straight road from the last stop to the office without stopping. Given that Aaron drove at the truck's average speed, which of the following values is closest to the time, in hours, Aaron drove on the return trip?          ", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "1", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "43. Use the following information to answer questions 41-43.The table below is part of a delivery truck log used in Aaron's trucking business. \"Mileage out\" and \"Mileage in\" represent the truck's mileage readings when it leaves the office and when it returns to the office, respectively, giving only the last 3 digits of the cumulative mileage reading. The \"Hours away\" column gives the amount of time from when the truck leaves the office until it returns to the office. When moving, the truck travels at an average speed of 50 miles per hour and does not travel more than 1,000 miles in any given day. Driver Ben forgot to complete the log for June 18.43. From June 17 through June 21, the average of the \u201cHours away\" was 5.50 hours. To the nearest 0.01, what is the value of \"Hours away\" when Ben was driving the truck?", "choices": {"A": "5.25", "B": "5.45", "C": "5.50", "D": "5.56", "E": "5.75"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "44. In \u25b3ABC shown below, the given side lengths are in meters. What is the area, in square meters, of \u25b3ABC?", "choices": {"A": "10", "B": "12", "C": "", "D": "", "E": "24"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "45. The value of log(x), to the nearest 0.1, is given in the table below for 4 different value of x.To the nearest 0.1, what is the value of log(3 \u00d7 105,000)?", "choices": {"A": "0.5", "B": "17.5", "C": "2,500.0", "D": "5,000.5", "E": "5,003,5"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "46. Susan completed 20 courses in college and her grade point average was 3.15(A = 4.0 and B = 3.0). If all of her grades were A's or B's, and each course grade carried equal weight, what is the number of A's that Susan received?", "choices": {"A": "1", "B": "3", "C": "4", "D": "9", "E": "15"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "47. The right semicircular cylinder shown below has a height of 5 centimeters and a semicircular base of radius 3 centimeters. What is the volume, in cubic centimeters, of the right semicircular cylinder?", "choices": {"A": "\u03c0", "B": "\u03c0", "C": "\u03c0", "D": "15\u03c0", "E": "45\u03c0"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "48. For positive real numbers M and N, ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "log(M - N)", "C": "log(N - M)", "D": " logM - logN", "E": "logN - logM"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "49. For what real number b, if any, will the equation a - 2b + ab = 2 be true for both a = 1 and a = -1?", "choices": {"A": "-2", "B": "-1", "C": "1", "D": "2", "E": "No such real number b exists."}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "50. Use the following information to answer question 50-52.Terri is a dress designer and owns a retail store. She designs, produces, and sells 5 dress styles. These styles and the production cost of 1 dress of each style are shown in the table below.50. Terri will hang 1 dress of each style along a rod in the window of her store. How many total possible orders (permutations) of these dresses are there for Terri to consider?", "choices": {"A": "1", "B": "5", "C": "25", "D": "120", "E": "3,125"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "51. Use the following information to answer question 50-52.Terri is a dress designer and owns a retail store. She designs, produces, and sells 5 dress styles. These styles and the production cost of 1 dress of each style are shown in the table below.51. Terri will offer a coupon in the local newspaper for 20% off the regular price of a dress. What is the regular price Terri must set for a Style B dress so that the the sale price using the coupon is exactly $15.00 more producing 1 Style B dress?", "choices": {"A": "$32.00", "B": "$45.00", "C": "$48.00", "D": "$50.00", "E": "$55.00"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "52. Use the following information to answer question 50-52.Terri is a dress designer and owns a retail store. She designs, produces, and sells 5 dress styles. These styles and the production cost of 1 dress of each style are shown in the table below.52. The labor cost of each dress is 40% of the production cost. What is the average labor cost per dress for dress of each of the 5 styles?", "choices": {"A": "$16.80", "B": "$25.20", "C": "$42.00", "D": "$84.00", "E": "$126.00"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "53.  It took 0.5 second for an object to travel 60.5 feet. To the nearest 0.01 mile per hour, what was the speed of the object?(Note: 1 mile = 5, 280 feet)", "choices": {"A": "30.25", "B": "61.00", "C": "82.50", "D": "87.30", "E": "121.00"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "54. Representatives of vectors u, v, p, q, and r are shown in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane below.One of the following vectors is equal to the vector u + v. Which one?", "choices": {"A": "-r", "B": "-q", "C": "-p", "D": "p", "E": "q"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "55.  In the standard (x, y) coordinate plane below, a shaded square is shown with vertices at (2, 3), (2, 4), (3, 3), and (3, 4). Two lines, y = rx and y = sx, each intersect the shaded square at exactly 1 point. Give that r \u2260s, what is the positive difference of r and s? ", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": "1"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "56. A random number generator that generates an integer through 6 will be used 15,000 times. Each time an integer is generated, the number will be recorded. Which of the following descriptors will most likely characterize the distribution of the 15,000 recorded numbers?", "choices": {"A": "Bimodal", "B": "Normal", "C": " Skewed left", "D": " Skewed right", "E": "Uniform"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "57.  In the standard (x, y) coordinate plane, define the h-v distance between 2 points to be the length, in coordinate units, of the shortest path between the 2 points using only horizontal and vertical segments. The expression |5 - 2| + |3 - (-4)| gives the h-v distance between which of the following pairs of points?", "choices": {"A": "(3, 5) and (-4, 2)", "B": "(3, 5) and (-2, 4)", "C": "(5, -4) and (-2, 3)", "D": "(5, -2) and (3, 4)", "E": "(5, 2) and (3, -4)"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "58.  Let m and s be the mean and standard deviation respectively, of the ages of children in a certain daycare center. Which of the following gives the mean and standard deviation of the ages of the same children 5 years later?", "choices": {"A": "Mean: m               Standard deviation: s", "B": "Mean: m               Standard deviation: s + 5", "C": "Mean: m + 5        Standard deviation: s", "D": "Mean: m + 5        Standard deviation: s + 5", "E": "Mean: m + 5        Standard deviation: 5s"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "59. The ellipse in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane below is the graph of . Which of the following points are the foci of the ellipse?", "choices": {"A": "(0, 3) and (5, 3)", "B": "(0, 3) and (10, 3)", "C": "(1, 3) and (5, 0)", "D": "(1, 3) and (9, 3)", "E": "(5, 0) and (5, 6)"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "60. Lucinda ran a 3-mile cross-country course in 24.0 minutes while Frannie ran the same course in 21.0 minutes. Which of the following values, in miles per hour, is closest to the difference between Frannie's average speed and Lucinda\u2019s average speed?", "choices": {"A": "0.1", "B": "1.0", "C": "1.1", "D": "1.5", "E": "3.0"}, "correct": "C"}]}